[car starting]
[engine revving]
[upbeat music playing]
[Jerry] This is a 1995
Volvo 960 station wagon.
Oh, my God. Really?
It is in regent red,
it has a black leather interior,
premium sound system and a sunroof.
But...
it was built with
a high-performance racing engine
by none other than Paul Newman.
It's a 380-horsepower Ford V8
with a supercharger
and a Mustang five-speed gearbox.
It looks like the kind of car
that you would take to a place like this.
And do things like this.
But it's actually a car
where you can do things like this.
[tires screeching]
[music pitches down and stops]
[brakes screech]
[tires screeching]
[music resumes]
[phone ringing]
-[David] Hello?
-[Jerry] Hello, Dave? It's Jerry.
-[David] Jerry...
-[Jerry] Seinfeld.
[David] Oh, yeah.
[Jerry] I was kind of
in the mood for coffee.
-Are you around?
-[David] Let's go.
[Jerry] Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and
this is Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today, my guest is talk show legend
David Letterman.
This Volvo is actually his car,
but he's letting me drive it today.
[dinging]
May I have two men, please?
-Is gay marriage legal in Connecticut?
-I don't believe so.
[engine revving]
Hi, Jerry, how are you? Nice to see you.
We're going for coffee.
Just wanted to let Mom know.
[jazz piano playing]
[David] I just love the car
because of Paul Newman.
He called me one day and he said, "A guy
is building me a Volvo station wagon
with a racing engine. Would you like one?"
And because it was Paul Newman,
you know, I was a little intimidated.
And I said, "Yes, I do, Paul.
I'd like one of those cars."
And he said,
"Great. Do you want a puffer on it?"
So I said, "Sure. Sure."
And I got off the phone and I said,
"Anybody know what a puffer is?"
-[Jerry chuckles]
-[David] And it's a supercharger.
-[Jerry] His sense of humor, isn't it?
-[David] Yes.
-[David] What is this?
-[Jerry] Well, Dave, it's a family car.
So today, this is the family.
That's me and that's you.
One day I had a cardiac appointment.
This was before my surgery.
So I said, "Great, we'll take the Volvo
into the city." [laughs]
And the car catches fire
on the Merritt Parkway.
[both chuckling]
The tailpipe coming off the manifold,
cherry red. Glowing.
Coulda killed me, I guess.
[both chuckling]
[Jerry] The hell with the cardiologist,
you were already in flames.
-[engine humming]
-[upbeat jazz playing]
[David] This is a treat for me.
You're driving the Paul Newman Volvo.
This is fantastic.
-[thuds]
-[grunts] Had it lowered a little.
[bell dings]
-What is that?
-Want kettle corn?
-How did you know I like kettle corn?
-I had a feeling.
[Jerry] So I took it to Stew Leonard's.
Have you been there?
[David] I went once, and I was
so frightened that I never went back.
Somewhere near "dairy,"
I abandoned the cart and ran out.
Is that your experience?
-Yeah, same thing happened to me.
-[laughs]
[Jerry] There was one guy
who had the trifecta.
He was hugely fat
pushing a giant load of food
-and chewing at the same time.
-Yeah.
He bought something probably
at the deli counter just to hold him over.
Yeah. Right.
Speaking of dumb guys,
how about this fella up here?
Yeah. "Speaking of dumb guys,"
always a segue.
[Jerry] This is a sensationally
well-done car.
[David] Not sure how well-done it is.
I remember taking my father-in-law out
in the car and then it just quit.
You ever been ten miles from your house
in a dead car with your father-in-law?
-No.
-That's a full day.
I mean, he's a wonderful man,
but that's a full day.
[Jerry] In the mood for coffee?
[David] I love coffee. Honest to God,
I can't get enough of it.
Now, can you get to a place where,
just for me, you can tap it a little bit?
Watch this.
[engine revving]
[David laughing]
Well, that's nice.
That's so nice, isn't it?
-Yeah.
-I mean, come on.
God bless Paul.
That did my heart good. Wow!
But, honest to God, it does smell
like we're seconds away
from incinerating something.
My feet are getting hot.
-[Jerry] It's just toasty in here.
-[David] The kettle corn is popping again.
[Jerry] You remember
The Comedy Store in the '70s?
Pryor would come in.
I had the, uh, the great fun
to follow him one night.
Because The Comedy Store, after Richard,
did everything but explode.
People are laughing so hard.
"And now, ladies and gentlemen,
Dave Letterman."
And of course, I have to fight people
who are leaving to get to the stage.
I kind of got friendly with Richard
and really thought he was a dear guy.
He closed with a bit about
having sex with a dog.
And I just thought, "Well, okay.
There are many facets of genius."
Yes, there are.
[David] Colin Quinn, I read a thing
in the Times where
he's like a big Twitter guy.
[Jerry] Big Twitter guy.
Your wife was quoted in the article.
She was? Yeah, maybe she was.
Everything all right at home?
[both laughing]
[Jerry] Remember in the '90s,
you were in LA,
and you came on the set of my show?
[audience laughing]
[audience cheering]
Oh, no, it's my weird cousin Larry.
-What are you guys talking about?
-Sandwiches.
Oh, man, don't get me started
on sandwiches.
[Jerry] That was so weird.
What do you think of my driving so far?
This'll be the real test,
the parallel parking.
Yeah. Well, watch this.
Oh, my! Ladies and gentlemen,
now that he's got his helmet off,
let's really let him hear it.
-Wow. That was impressive.
-That's what they say at Indy?
-Yeah.
-Now that he's got his helmet off...
Yeah. Let's really let him hear it.
-[Jerry] Do you want any more kettle corn?
-No, thanks.
Come over,
I want you to look at something.
-I mean...
-How you doing?
-Good, Randy, how are you?
-You're here.
-I mean, if we were robbing a bank...
-Hey, Bill. Hey, Randy.
-Bill. Randy.
-[Randy] Hey.
-[upbeat jazz piano playing]
-[no audible dialogue]
-[Jerry] I'd like some coffee. Yeah.
-[waitress] Sure.
I'd like some coffee as well, please.
[hissing]
[Jerry] What time did you get up
this morning?
[David] I got up at 7:00.
First, we take the dog out,
and it's, uh, Frisbee.
Then it's shovel time.
-You have to get up with your dog?
-[Jerry] No.
In the apartment we have... There's
a little paper thing, they go on that.
Has the Board of Health
signed off on that?
[Jerry] Yeah, they gave us a C.
Not drinking coffee if you're not
drinking it black. Don't you think?
-No, I don't think.
-You like to monkey with it?
[laughs]
Now I'm afraid to talk
because of these people.
Or are these actors?
[Jerry] No, they're people, Dave.
Can we just ask these people to leave?
We don't own this place.
[both laughing]
We could change that though, can't we?
You know, you've had so many fantastic
lines that you've done on your show.
Do those rattle around your head ever
or are they all gone?
Sometimes somebody will,
"Remember the time..." and I'll say,
"Really, I said that?"
Do you remember the woman that said,
"Have you ever had the hump of a camel?"
I had a, um... Have you ever had
the hump of a camel?
[audience laughing]
-Yeah, I do remember that.
-Yeah. And there was that long beat.
And I wondered if you had it right away
or you were...
Or it came as... In that laugh.
What I do remember, "Is the double meaning
that I'm leveraging this joke on
gonna hold up?"
No, I've, uh... I've never had
the hump of a camel.
-[audience laughing]
-I didn't think so.
But I must say, when I was younger,
I was pretty good.
[audience laughing]
So you have?
[audience cheering]
-[David] I knew it was a setup.
-Right.
But I didn't know that "hump" would be
the fulcrum, you know?
Yeah, and you think, "Gee, I don't wanna
waste this fat pitch on something."
But it really was so great.
-But I'll tell you, often, somebody...
-Right.
-Thank you.
-[waitress] You're welcome.
[David] Sure.
Something from the lab, apparently.
[laughing] Yes.
Have you found football
any harder to watch?
I think they should get rid of time-outs.
They should get rid of punts.
And also,
I think they should be allowed to play
as many guys as they'd like.
If you got a play for 40 guys,
send them in.
Your team, uh, gets
three successive first downs.
They then have the option
of running a play with two balls.
Feel like I'm in Gallagher's act now.
[both laughing]
That is a little "Gallagher."
Here's something I'm good at,
going to the hardware store.
-I love going to the hardware store.
-Yeah.
And my son, we were in
the hardware store one day and he says...
[sniffing]
"I love how it smells here." I said...
-Smells great. Smells great.
-Smells fantastic. Yeah.
Over the winter
we built a little push car.
So he goes down the driveway,
loses control and goes over like this.
But it was all pretty minor.
Two hours later,
his first baseball practice of the season.
So now he says, "I can't go to baseball
practice because I've hurt my hand."
-Right.
-So, what do you do in that situation?
I support whatever position my wife takes.
-[laughing]
-That's what I do.
Because she knows more
about parenting than you?
The answer: Doesn't matter what you do.
-But why have a fight with your wife?
-The... [chuckles]
Yeah. But the worst part of that is...
Maybe you don't experience this
since you mentioned that you don't care.
[both laughing]
Is that you feel guilty
about your own behavior.
You know, I kind of look at my family now
and I think,
"Well, in 60 years everyone's dead here."
So... [laughing]
Could I have the check, please?
Good Lord!
-Oh, my goodness!
-It's just that...
I just don't like this over-consideration
of every decision that's...
Well, that's me.
If I had more than one,
I'd feel a little more comfortable about
the decisions
I would make with either one.
You've used that excuse a number of times.
I don't buy it.
You're gonna react to two the same as one.
A kid is a kid.
-That's what I've heard.
-Kid's a kid.
I agree that being an older parent,
a lot of the real serious stuff,
I'll be dead for.
You don't know that.
I don't know that,
but sometimes it's useful.
[laughing]
What if he told you
he wanted to be a comedian?
I don't think that'll come up.
His stepfather, Scott, will...
will deal with that.
Scott will get him into a hedge fund.
[both laughing]
The comedy universe is a swamp of madness.
-Yes.
-Haven't you enjoyed in your life,
that you've been really surrounded by it?
The Comedy Store.
I mean, it was one after another
of guys who were really funny
-and guys who had personality disorders.
-Yeah.
[David] Lenny Schultz comes to mind.
-[Jerry] You saw him?
-[David] Oh, my God.
We talk about Lenny Schultz
once a week now.
I remember one time
Lenny's got a BabyBjorn thing.
And he's running around onstage with the
plastic doll and he has a little toy whip.
-Right.
-And he's whipping the baby.
Because you hear the sound effects
of a crying baby.
And then, Lenny is whipping the baby.
"Be quiet. William Morris is here.
Stop it. William Morris is
looking at my act. Stop it, baby."
And he's whipping the plastic doll.
Because William Morris
is taking a look at it.
It was delightful.
And where did you go on
in the very beginning?
-Comedy Store. Yeah.
-First time onstage?
-Did you get any laughs?
-No.
-Nothing?
-No. No.
-I remember being shocked by the quiet.
-Mm-hmm.
'Cause I had watched
a lot of comedians and thought,
"Well, the audience seems to be
laughing anyway."
And then when you go up there,
you find out they're not laughing at all.
I had to go to a place in Denver, uh,
called the Turn of the Century.
And I was opening for Leslie Uggams.
Wow!
And you're supposed to do 45 minutes.
-To open?
-To open.
-Well, I had about 35.
-[chuckles] Right.
And the guarantee is
they were gonna turn the house.
-Right.
-They didn't turn the house.
So, the second show, it's,
"Hi, where you from?"
And the guy says, "I'm from Denver."
And I said, "Ah. Great, Denver."
And I said,
"Where are you from?" "Denver."
And the guy says, "Look,
we're all from Denver. You're in Denver."
I said, "Thank you, good night.
And now Leslie Uggams."
[both laughing]
You guys want something?
[David] I'm really not hungry.
-But get something for yourself.
-Okay. [laughs]
Leonard used to say that wherever we'd go.
[imitating Leonard] "Not hungry,
-but get something for yourself."
-[waitress laughs]
Ever eaten with him?
I... I remember, uh, years ago he was
living with a woman named Adele.
He called up and says:
[imitating Leonard] "Letterman,
why don't you come over
and we'll write some jokes and stuff."
I said, "Great,"
knowing full well that
there's nothing I could contribute to Jay.
-Right.
-And I go over there and it's noontime,
and Adele brings him out,
what looked like an enormous,
I don't know, porterhouse.
I don't know,
a big fallen-over-the-platter
-piece of steak.
-Right.
He... He gets right into it.
And then she comes out
with a, uh, carton of milk,
a gallon carton of milk.
[chuckles] And he's drinking the milk,
and his face is now
glistening with meat grease.
And there was never any question of:
[imitating Leonard]
"Can I get you something to eat?"
Never happened.
Yeah, the few times I've watched him eat,
my only thought is, "Let me just
not get my hand caught in there."
It's like a combine.
One night we had Rickles on,
and we had Regis on,
and we had Tony Bennett on.
-The same show?
-On the same show.
-It was for the kids.
-[Jerry chuckles]
But that, to me, was reminiscent
of Johnny in Burbank.
Did Johnny talk to you during commercials?
He would sometimes
give me stuff about bits.
He would say,
"Why don't you try this or that?"
-He did that to a lot of guys.
-What good is it now?
I've already burned it here.
[both laughing]
When in your timeline
did you start guesting on that show?
May 7th, 1981.
So, the pressure of--
-Either I have a career or I don't.
-Right. Exactly right.
-Right?
-Yep.
Like, I either make it or break it,
right here, right now.
-The guy pulls the curtain open...
-Yeah.
-...and the rest of your life is there.
Jonathan Winters dropped dead
the other day. That's just God-awful.
-Did you love Jonathan Winters?
-Absolutely.
Adored him.
He would come out on The Ed Sullivan Show
and I would start laughing
when he came out.
Yes. I don't think comedy has changed
and it ever will change.
What about the mechanism of comedy?
No. No change.
-No change?
-No change.
You don't care, uh, if a guy's doing
his "having sex with a dog" bit.
As long as they don't make me do it,
I don't care.
It's justice.
Comedy is the closest thing to justice.
If you're funny, you survive.
If you're not, you don't.
Lenny Schultz, God bless him,
you know, he would be doing great now.
I can remember for a time
he had a little person in his act.
And his name was Corky.
And he would invite Corky...
up onstage to sit on his lap and...
[chuckling]
We'll just let it go at that.
You be the judge. Is that--
Do you think there was a meeting
of little people to decide,
"Well, what should we be called?"
Do you think they sat around and said,
"Look, we gotta
get rid of this midget thing.
We need another term of our own choosing."
Do you think such a meeting
ever took place?
Yes, I... I believe that there was.
And what do you think some of the other...
I don't know.
Do you think "fun-size"
came into the conversation?
I knew you were working on material.
[both laughing]
Do you find yourself
always trying to be funny
and sometimes people
just don't wanna be bothered or...
Yeah, pretty regularly.
-Regularly?
-Yeah.
Now, is this about how long
you talk to your guests on this show?
No, this is longer.
Why is that?
-I think we're getting on.
-Oh. Oh, okay.
I thought maybe you were still waiting
for something good to happen.
Oh, no.
[laughing] You gave...
You gave up on that.
Let's get out of here.
Wanna check out that hardware store?
[David] Mm-hmm.
-[Jerry] Let's see if it has the smell.
-[David] It will.
[David laughing]
There it is. [sniffing]
-That's it.
-What is that?
I don't know, it's fantastic.
Is someone helping you?
-Are you looking for a grill? Oh.
-No.
Did we just pin you in
and you're trying to get out?
-Yes.
-[David] She's being held hostage. Run.
Run for your life, ma'am.
-[Jerry] Bye, thank you.
-[woman] Have a great day.
-Now here's where the car breaks down...
-[laughing]
...and we're stuck here
for the rest of the night.
-Do you have the keys, Jerry?
-Yeah, I got them.
[Jerry] Could we try driving
one of your other cars?
[David] Can I pick the car?
-[Jerry] Sure.
-[David] Okay.
-[metal grinding]
-[David groans]
[David] Thanks for that kettle corn.
In addition to being delicious,
it was hilarious.
[both laughing]
Thank you.
Oh, no, not this.
[laughing]
-[Jerry] No, I won't.
-[David] Yeah.
Oh, God, I don't wanna be in this.
[David] First time I drove it,
it was so quiet, I ran over a squirrel.
-You really don't like riding in this car.
-[Jerry] No.
[David] You just wanna burn up
as much fossil fuel as you can.
[Jerry] It's like alcohol, Dave.
We have a problem with this stuff.
Let's finish it up.
[David laughing]
[David] People just make fun of me
when they see me in this car.
-And I feel like a putz, you know?
-[Jerry] Right.
Do you know what a putz is?
[David] Well, I... Yeah.
-[Jerry] Know the word "schmuck"?
-[David] Yeah.
[Jerry] So, what's the difference?
[David] A schmuck would be a guy
riding around with a putz
while he's eating kettle corn.
[Jerry chuckling]
Is that how that breaks out?
[David chuckling]
I'm driving till the red light
comes on, buddy.
Let me show you what we got here.
I was in Montana, and I put my car, uh...
Ran it off the road, put it in a pond.
It's 7:00 in the morning,
it's 15 degrees and it's snowing.
Within ten minutes, a woman picks me up,
takes me to a guy's house...
-You're on your own in this car? Yeah.
-I'm on my own.
And we're heading back toward the house,
and I see the guys coming.
I get out, I get in with the guys,
they hook it up to a chain,
they pop it out so that the rear end
is airborne.
They just yanked it out.
Kaboom! Comes flying out.
I said, "Thank you very much, boys."
I get back in the car.
-It was tremendous.
-Wow! That's tremendous.
Yes, it's just wonderful.
Now, if it had been me,
they'd find me dead in the car.
-Right. It's Misery.
-Yeah.
[Jerry] You're meeting Kathy Bates
and getting hobbled.
[David chuckling]
[Jerry] I love getting hobbled.